Don't leave Earth without it.
The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy is a adventure, comedy,
science fiction film directed by Garth Jennings.
Mere seconds before the Earth is to be demolished by an alien construction crew, Arthur Dent is swept off the planet by
his friend Ford Prefect, a researcher penning a new edition of "The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy."
Arthur Dent, played by Martin Freeman.
Ford Prefect, played by Yasiin Bey.
Trillian, played by Zooey Deschanel.
Zaphod Beeblebrox, played by Sam Rockwell.
Marvin (voice), played by Alan Rickman.
Questular Rontok, played by Anna Chancellor.
The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy is a 2005 science fiction comedy film directed by Garth
Jennings, based upon the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy series created by Douglas Adams.
It stars Martin Freeman, Sam Rockwell, Yasiin Bey (credited as Mos Def), Zooey Deschanel, Bill Nighy, Anna Chancellor, and John
Malkovich, and the voices of Stephen Fry, Helen Mirren, Richard Griffiths, Thomas Lennon, Ian McNeice, and Alan Rickman.
Adams co-wrote the screenplay with Karey Kirkpatrick, and the film is
dedicated to Adams, who died in 2001 before production began.
The film received mainly positive reviews and
grossed over $100 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of galaxy, android,
bureaucracy, based on novel or book, chase.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.